phaseone.com 2019-07-10

# Phase One Cookie Policy

1.                 Background and purpose

Phase One (we" / “our” / “us”) use cookies on our website at [www.phaseone.com](http://www.phaseone.com/), [www.captureone.com](https://www.captureone.com/), and all associated subdomains to improve the websites’ performance and enhance the user experience. By continuing to use the website you agree to our use of cookies.

Website owner contact information:

Phase One A/S

Roskildevej 39

DK-2000 Frederiksberg 

Company registration no.: 17 88 96 99

E-mail: legal@phaseone.com

2.                 Applicability, responsibility and approval

This Cookie Policy applies when we use cookies to collect data, including personal data, from a device which accesses our website or uses our services available through online resources. 

This Phase One Cookie Policy is updated as required and at least once a year to ensure relevance and topicality. 

**3.                 ** **What are cookies?** ****

Cookies are data files placed and stored on your computer or mobile device for collection of select use data and are useful as they allow a website to recognize a user's device and history of use.

Some types of cookies are only stored on your device as long as your browser is open, so-called session cookies. Other types of cookies are stored on your device for a longer period of time, so-called persistent cookies. For both types of cookies, the cookie is automatically renewed when you return to a cookie enabled website.

Cookies deriving from other parties than us may also be placed on your device; so-called third-party cookies. Such cookies may be cookies performing ordinary functions or analysis tools and embedded comments fields. 

We use cookies to analyze how users use our website and to create the most secure and effective website possible for our users. By indicating how and when visitors use the website, cookies aid us in finding out which areas are popular and which areas are not, and how we can improve the user experience. The cookies allow us to improve your experience when using our website and to ensure the site performs as you expect it to. Improvements and updates of the website are based on information supplied by cookies.

Further, cookies help us to personalize web content and meet the desires of our visitors. Among other things, we use cookies to allow you to choose log-in preferences and to buy products and services in our online store. We use cookies to safeguard your privacy. Our website does not use cookies to collect personal information from your computer that was not initially sent as a cookie. We never store passwords or similarly sensitive data in cookies.  
~~~~

~~4~~ **. **          ****Cookies on phaseone.com****

We use cookies on [https://www.phaseone.com](https://www.phaseone.com/), [https://www.captureone.com](https://www.captureone.com/), and all associated phaseone.com and captureone.com subdomains to collect information about your device when your device accesses or uses our services. The cookie, the functionality and the collected information varies. For the time being, the applied cookies collect the information detailed in sections 5 and 6.

**5.                  **********First-party cookies****

We use session cookies, which are deleted when you close your browser. We also use persistent first-party cookies, which are stored between 30 days and up to two years. Both types of cookies register:

·       _Log Information:_ we log information about your use of our services, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, acceptance of the cookie policy, and the page you visited before navigating to our website.  

·       _Device information:_ we collect information about the device you use to access our services, including information about the device’s software and hardware, Media Access Control (“MAC”) address and other unique device identifiers, device token, mobile network information, geographic location, and time zone identifying your http requests when using the website.  

·       _Usage information:_ we collect information relating to your use and consumption of our Software and Services, including what software versions and functionality you use, how often you use (click) buttons and menu items, execution times for specific operations, user experienced stability of the Software and Services, exceptions and generated error/crash reports.  

·       _Anonymization:_ we use a general purpose platform cookie to maintain an anonymized user session by the server.

6.                 **Third-party cookies**

We collaborate with advertisers, media agencies, and networks who use cookies on our website. The purpose of such cookies is generally to enable the delivery of personalized content by Phase One and to ensure the delivery of targeted online ads on behalf of our collaborative partners. Therefore, the following companies also place session or persistent cookies on www.phaseone.com:

·       **Facebook** places a cookie called Pixel, enabling the website to recognize your browsing information. The cookie enables conversion analytics from Facebook advertising, and allows us to deliver targeted ads on the Facebook platform based on actions you take on our website. Facebook cookies are stored for up to 1 year.   

·     **Google Analytics** places session and persistent cookies. The session cookies are deleted when you close the browser. The persistent cookies are stored for up to two years. The cookies are used to distinguish unique users by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier. It is included in each page request in a site and used to calculate visitor, session and campaign data for the site’s analytics reports.  

·     **Marketo** places a persistent cookie called Munchkin, which is stored for one year. The tracking cookie allows the website to link visitor behavior to the recipient of an email marketing campaign to measure campaign effectiveness. The cookie also stores the general web behavior of a visitor in an anonymized form, which is then linked to a person when they provide personal information via a form.  

·     **Visual Website Optimizer** , a product by Wingify, places a persistent cookie which is stored for one year. The tool helps site owners measure the performance of different versions of web pages. This cookie ensures the visitor always sees the same version of a page and is used to track behavior to measure the performance of different page versions.  

·     **AddThis** is a social sharing widget, which places a persistent cookie which is stored for 13 months. The widget enables visitors to share content with a range of sharing platforms. The cookie stores an updated page share count.

**7.                  ****Links to other websites** ****

Our website may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that Phase One is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third-party websites as well as any information they might collect, even though our name or logo may appear on those sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the Privacy statements of each and every website that you visit, as the privacy policy of those sites may differ from ours. 

8.                 ********How do you delete or disable cookies?****

The browsers of most computers, smartphones and other web-enabled devices are typically set up to accept cookies. You have the option to control the acceptance of cookies yourself and, if you wish, to block them entirely by configuring your Internet browser. Please refer to the documentation for your browser to change your cookie preferences.

The procedure for deleting or disabling cookies on your device depends on the browser you are using.

If you are using a PC, you may delete cookies by using the keyboard shortcut [CTRL]+[SHIFT]+[Delete]

If this procedure is not successful or if you are using a Mac computer, please follow the guidelines via the following links depending on the browser you are using:

·       [Internet Explorer](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-gb/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies#ie=ie-8)

·       [Mozilla Firefox](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored?redirectlocale=en-US&redirectslug=Deleting+cookies)

·       [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en-GB)

·       [Opera](http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/)

·       [Safari](http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1677?viewlocale=en_US)

·       [Flash cookies](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html)

All Danish websites are required to inform users about the cookies placed on their device. The information must comply with the “Executive Order on Information and Consent required in case of Storing or Accessing Information in End-user Terminal Equipment", the so-called Cookie Order ( _cookie bekendtgørelsen_ ).

·       [Link to Executive Order](https://www.retsinformation.dk/Forms/R0710.aspx?id=139279)  
·       [Link to Guidelines](https://www.retsinformation.dk/Forms/R0710.aspx?id=140089)

Please remember that cookies are used to enable and improve certain functions on our website. If you choose to switch certain cookies off, it is likely to affect how our website works.

**9.                  ****Questions** ****

If you have any questions about cookies, please contact us on legal@phaseone.com.

To find out more about how we protect your privacy when using our website, see our [Privacy Policy](https://www.phaseone.com/Legal/Privacy-Policy).
